Feel the jungle beat
The Jungle Book 2 is a family, animation, adventure
film directed by Steve Trenbirth.
Mowgli has been living in the man-village with his little
stepbrother Ranjan and his best friend Shanti.
But the man-cub still has that jungle rhythm in his heart, and
he misses his old buddies Baloo and Bagheera.
When Mowgli wanders back to the wild for some swingin' fun, he soon finds the
man-eating tiger Shere Khan is lurking in the shadows and planning his revenge.
Mowgli (voice), played by Haley Joel Osment.
Baloo (voice), played by John Goodman.
Shanti (voice), played by Mae Whitman.
Ranjan (voice), played by Connor Funk.
Bagheera (voice), played by Bob Joles.
Shere Khan (voice), played by Tony Jay.
The Jungle Book 2 is a 2003 animated adventure film produced by the Australian office at
DisneyToon Studios and released by Walt Disney Pictures and Buena Vista Distribution.
The film was released in France on February 5, 2003, and
released in the United States on February 14.
The film is a sequel to Walt Disney's 1967 film The Jungle Book, and stars Haley Joel
Osment as the voice of Mowgli and John Goodman as the voice of Baloo.
The film was originally produced as a direct-to-video film, but was released
theatrically first, similar to the Peter Pan sequel Return to Never Land.
It is the fourth animated Disney sequel to have a theatrical release rather than going direct-to-video after The Rescuers Down Under
(1990), Fantasia 2000 (1999), and Return to Never Land (2002) and the last one until Ralph Breaks the Internet (2018).
The film is not based on The Second Jungle Book, but
they do have several characters in common.
The film received negative reviews criticizing the animation and plot, but it was a box
office success, grossing $135.7 million against a $20 million budget.
The film explores themes of tiger, river, village, cartoon, musical.
The tone is lighthearted.